The true story that inspired The Man Who Would Be King
Edge of the World is a drama, adventure, history
film directed by Michael Haussman.
Sarawak, in the northeast of the island of Borneo, 1839.
Almost by chance, the British adventurer James Brooke is appointed rajah by the Sultan of Brunei, and as an independent ruler he embarks on a personal
crusade to eradicate piracy, slavery and headhunting, while trying to curb the malevolent expansionist ambitions of the British Empire.
Sir James Brooke, played by Jonathan Rhys Meyers.
Madame Lim, played by Josie Ho.
Crookshank, played by Dominic Monaghan.
Elizabeth Crookshank, played by Hannah New.
Sir Edward Beech, played by Ralph Ineson.
Pengiran Indera Mahkota, played by Bront Palarae.
Edge of the World (also known as Rajah) is a 2021 adventure drama film directed by Michael Haussman and starring Jonathan
Rhys Meyers as the British soldier and adventurer James Brooke (1803–1868), the first White Rajah of Sarawak.
The film also features Atiqah Hasiholan, Dominic
Monaghan, Hannah New, and Josie Ho.
The script was written by Rob Allyn, who also produced the film.
Edge of the World is a co-production of Malaysia, China, the US and the UK.
The tone is emotional.